Documentary about the history of Pixar animation
The Pixar Story is a documentary film directed by Leslie Iwerks.
A look at the first years of Pixar Animation Studios - from the success of "Toy Story" and Pixar's promotion of talented people, to the
building of its East Bay campus, the company's relationship with Disney, and its remarkable initial string of eight hits.
The contributions of John Lasseter, Ed Catmull and Steve Jobs are profiled.
The decline of two-dimensional animation is chronicled
as three-dimensional animation rises.
Hard work and creativity seem to share the screen in equal proportions.
Narrator (voice), played by Stacy Keach.
Self, played by Edwin Catmull.
Self, played by Steve Jobs.
Self, played by John Lasseter.
Self, played by William Reeves.
Self - Heimlich/ Lenny, played by Joe Ranft.
Pixar Animation Studios is an American CGI film production company
based in Emeryville, California, United States.
Pixar has produced 29 feature films, which were all released by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures through the Walt Disney Pictures banner, with its first being Toy
Story (which was also the first CGI-animated feature ever theatrically released) on November 22, 1995, and its latest being Elio on June 20, 2025.
Its upcoming slate of films includes  Hoppers and Toy Story 5 in 2026,
Gatto in 2027, and Incredibles 3 and Coco 2 in 2028 or later.
The film explores themes of movie business, behind the
scenes, computer animation, woman director.